Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Part II - Correspondence
  - AUGUST 1970
    - French translation of Penelope Gilliat article partly on J.R. - Joseph McBride interviews J.R. - Re. PETIT THEATRE: reports on Langlois screening at Metropolitan Museum without subtitles, completion of Weinberg subtitles with notes from J.R. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Gilliatt, Penelope * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Curtis, Tony * McBride, Joseph * Weinberg, Herman * Langlois, Henri (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - SEPTEMBER 1970
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: distribution, subtitling issues continued, correspondence with Weinberg re. wording of subtitles - J.R. postpones home video project, plans to have camera repaired - Text of Leo Braudy interview with J.R., plus notes - Planned apearance at AFI seminar Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Langlois, Henri * Long, Pierre * Weinberg, Herman * Braudy, Leo (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - OCTOBER 1970
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: subtitling issues continued - J.R. writes statement for Weinberg book SAINT CINEMA - Charles Samuels requests interview for book ENCOUNTERING DIRECTORS - J.R. has donated papers to Harvard - J.R. writes Preface for Soviet book on J.R. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Eisner, Lotte * Weinberg, Herman * Carmet, Jean (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - NOVEMBER 1970
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: distribution and subtitling issues continued, broadcast scheduled 15 Dec. - J.R. said to be Nazi sympathizer in book on Saint-Exupery - Clippings on DIRECTION D'ACTEUR - J.R. writes statement on Frank Silvera - J.R. declines to sell project "Julienne", hoping CAPITAINE GEORGES will be produced - Continued attempts to obtain rights over old films - J.R. stops taking L-Dopa Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * DIRECTION D'ACTEUR, LA * Beylie, Claude * Bergman, Ingrid * Braudy, Leo * Cassan, Marguerite * Silvera, Frank * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - DECEMBER 1970
    - Reaction to book on Saint-Exupery - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: subtitling issues continued, 15 Dec. broadcast in France, reactions - J.R. health issues continued - J.R. starts writing a book - J.R. appearance at AFI - Museum of Modern Art plans J.R. retrospective for March Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Truffaut, Francois * Griot, Jean (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Personal correspondence. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - JANUARY 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: more reactions, subtitling issues continued - Discussions on adaptation of CAPITAINE GEORGES continued - Financial conflict with Braunberger - Conflict with Paul Renoir continues (every month) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Braunberger, Pierre * Renoir, Paul (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - FEBRUARY 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: distribution and subtitling issues continued - Video rights issue - J.R. hospitalized - J.R. assists Claude Beylie with filmography for Bazin book on J.R. - J.R. reaction to LITTLEMURDERS - J.R. appears at Writers Guild - J.R. retrospectives planned at USC, Madrid Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Long, Pierre * Reisner, Joel * Arkin, Alan * Bazin, Andre (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - MARCH 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R. writes preface for Bazin book - Discussion of CAHIERS DU CINEMA - J.R. seeking English subtitled prints of GRANDE ILLUSION and BOUDU - Video rights issue, re. Kirschner desire to make film on J.R Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Bazin, Andre * Truffaut, Francois * Moreau, Jeanne * Olaf, Pierre (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - APRIL 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Plans for May radio interview with Simenon Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Dieudonne, Albert * Simenon, Georges * Bergman, Ingrid (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - MAY 1971
    - J.R. declines Welles invitation to appear in THE OTHER SIDE OF THE WIND (includes sides) - Correspondence with Ginette - Video rights issues continued - Simon & Schuster publication of LA REGLE DU JEU scenario - Discussion of J.R. materials previously donated to Cinemateque (for tax purposes) - Health troubles continued - Re. PETIT THEATRE: Italian TV desire to change order of episodes, subtitling, distribution issues continued Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Welles, Orson * Doynel, Ginette * REGLE DU JEU, LA * Langlois, Henri * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * BAS FONDS, LES * Olaf, Pierre (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - JUNE 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: distribution issues continued - Lebovici considers staging CAROLA - Bazin book on J.R. published in France Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * CAROLA * Lebovici, Gerard * Reiner, Carl * Bazin, Andre (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - JULY 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. Bazin book: reaction, J.R. reaction to Hugh Gray desire to translate - J.R. picks his 4 favorite films for French TV broadcast (including Ginette suggestion) - Museum of Modern Art retrospective put off to Sept. - J.R. becomes member Board of Directors of Friends of Cinematheque Francaise Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Bazin, Andre * Gray, Hugh * Bergman, Ingrid * Olaf, Pierre (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - AUGUST 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R. becomes member of Coordinating Council of USC School of Performing Arts Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Langlois, Henri (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - SEPTEMBER 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R.'s falls, injures himself, is bedridden - Copy of Polan Banks article on J.R. for Playboy Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Moreau, Jeanne * Cassan, Marguerite * MADAME BOVARY * RIVER, THE * Agel, Henri * Banks, Polan * Braunberger, Pierre (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - OCTOBER 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Agel, Henri * Cassan, Marguerite (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - NOVEMBER 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R.'s health improves, he hires a secretary - THE RIVER re-released? Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - DECEMBER 1971
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: Distribution issues continued, Italian broadcast - Copy of piece by J.R. on THE RIVER Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * RIVER, THE * McEldowney, Kenneth (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Personal correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Eisner, Lotte * Sesonske, Alexander (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - JANUARY 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Discussion of rights to THE RIVER - Ginette working on "La Compagnie J.R." - J.R. reaction to book LA MORT DE L'ART - J.R. presents THE RIVER on KCET broadcast - U.S. broadcast of J.R. films with Champlin interview Includes correspondence regarding or with: * RIVER, THE * McEldowney, Kenneth * Reiniger, Lotte * Champlin, Charles * Carmet, Jean (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - FEBRUARY 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R. interviewed by Charles Samuels for book ENCOUNTERING DIRECTORS, and by Marcella Katz for UCLA dissertation - Eisenschitz, CAHIERS DU CINEMA, preparing book of J.R. writings and interviews - Winnipeg Art Gallery schedules J.R. retrospective for May Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Samuels, Charles * Katz, Marcella * Eisenschitz, Bernard * Cassan, Marguerite (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - MARCH 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Ginette finds pre-War J.R. papers: poetry, scripts, discussion of donation to UCSB/Sesonske - Proposal to adapt ORVET as stage musical - J.R. reaction to Richard Avedon book - Leo Braudy book on J.R.published, J.R. reaction - J.R. interview with L.A. Times' Digby Diehl? Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * ORVET * Braudy, Leo * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES * Avedon, Richard (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - APRIL 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - ORVET adaptation discussions continued - J.R. seeks info on negatives of his films - Discussion of staging CAROLA with Moreau - PETIT THEATRE subtitling issues continued - Bebe Allan's conrtinued attempts to find producer to adapt CAPITAINE GEORGES for film Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Moreau, Jeanne * ORVET * CAROLA * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Shuen, Shu * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - MAY 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - PETIT THEATRE subtitling issues continued - List of J.R.'s jazz records - Moreau receives proposal for U.S. TV version of CAROLA - Philosophical correspondence with Henry Miller - J.R. consents to interviews re. Robert, Frances Flaherty, Bertolt Brecht, plus personal interview with Michael Gould Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * CAROLA * Moreau, Jeanne * Miller, Henry * Flaherty, Robert * Brecht, Bertolt * Braunberger, Pierre (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - JUNE 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - ORVET adaptation discussions continued - J.R. reflections on film distribution troubles in letter to Guy Cavagnac - Administration des Monnaies et Medailles creates J.R. medal - J.R. "Notes on THE RIVER" Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * ORVET * RIVER, THE (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - JULY 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R.'s health worsens - J.R. interview with James Lyon re. Bertolt Brecht Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Ryan, Robert * Caron, Leslie * Bergman, Ingrid * Brecht, Bertolt * Lyon, James (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - AUGUST 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - PETIT THEATRE subtitling issues continued - Continued health problems - J.R. grants interview to Albrecht Betz re. Hans Eisler Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Moreau, Jeanne * Betz, ALbrecht * Eisler, Hanns (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - SEPTEMBER 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Continued health problems - CAROLA script sent to Gregory Peck - Helen Strauss interested in adapting RENOIR, MON PERE for screen, directed by George Cukor Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * CAROLA * Peck, Gregory * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * Cukor, George * Strauss, Helen (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - OCTOBER 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - RENOIR, MON PERE adaptation discussions continued - CAROLA produced for U.S. TV - RAI (Italian TV) to arrange English subtitles for PETIT THEATRE for Museum of Modern Art screening - J.R. gives permission for TV adaptation of ORVET Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * RENOIR PAR RENOIR * CAROLA * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * ORVET (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - NOVEMBER 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette, including J.R.'s thoughts on the political situation - J.R. reaction to Claude Beylie dissertation on J.R., discussion of realism (see earlier Beylie correspondence, not indexed) Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Beylie, Claude * Schlesinger, John (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - DECEMBER 1972
    - Correspondence with Ginette - PETIT THEATRE subtitling issues continued Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Braunberger, Pierre * Brialy, Jean-Claude (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Personal note from Doris Kenyon Mlynarski. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - JANUARY 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - J.R. completes draft of autobiography, correspondence with Robert Knittel re. revisions - J.R. reaction to advanced screening of CAROLA - Efforts to preserve LA PETITE MARCHANDE D'ALLUMETTES - Renoir/Truffaut discussion of English - PETIT THEATRE screened at Museum of Modern Art, dubbed into Italian, subtitled in English - Reviews of CAROLA Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * CAROLA * Caron, Leslie * PETITE MARCHANDE D'ALLUMETTES * Truffaut, Francois * Knittel, Robert * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - FEBRUARY 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette, discussion of J.R. draft of autobiography - Problems with PETIT THEATRE screening - Re. CAROLA: U.S. broadcast, reactions, J.R. desire for French production - J.R. authorizes Museum of Modern Art to acquire prints of his films - Continued attempts to produce CAPITAINE GEORGES Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * CAROLA * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Simenon, Georges * Kershner, Irvin * CAHIERS DU CAPT. GEORGES, LES (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - MARCH 1973
    - Correpondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: discussions of content with Ginette, Robert Knittel, Dido description of J.R. work habits - J.R. gives away video camera - Death of David Loew Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Beylie, Claude * Sesonske, Alexander * Loew, David (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - APRIL 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Continued efforts to preserve J.R.'s old films - Re. autobiography: J.R. rewriting, discussions with Ginette, decision to publish in U.S. with Athenuem - Sesonske attempt to obtain print of LA VIE EST A NOUS Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Sesonske, Alexander * VIE EST A NOUS, LA (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - MAY 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Continued efforts to preserve J.R.'s old films and obtain copies - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. writing and French publication Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - JUNE 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: discussions of provisional title, SOUVENIRS INCOMPLETS, nature of book's incompleteness, French vs. American period - Financial statements for Compagnie Jean Renoir - Continued attempts to obtain prints of old J.R. films - Sale of LA PETITE MARCHANDE D'ALLUMETTES to French TV to cover cost of new print Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Carmet, Jean (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - JULY 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: discussions on content, publication, representation, translation - Success of Bazin book on J.R. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Knittel, Robert * Bazin, Andre (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - AUGUST 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. J.R.'s health: Dr. Bruck diagnoses mental block preventing improvement, sends psychologist, J.R. comments to Ginette - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. publication, title, translation- Possibility of publishing CAROLA - Continued success of Bazin book on J.R. - J.R. reaction to Weinberg book SAINT CINEMA Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Gallimard, Gaston * CAROLA * Bazin, Andre * Knittel, Robert * Bessie, Simon Michael * Weinberg, Herman (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - SEPTEMBER 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. PETIT THEATRE: subtitling, distribution issues continued - ECRITS proposed - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. publication Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Weinberg, Herman * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Truffaut, Francois * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * ECRITS, 1926-1971 * Gauteur, Claude (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - OCTOBER 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. publication, translation, copy of contract - ECRITS discussions - Copy of NEW YORKER article on Truffaut containing discussion of J.R. - J.R. text on Pagnol - J.R. turns down request for interview for documentary on love/sex in J.R.'s films Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * Gauteur, Claude * Knittel, Robert * Bessie, Simon Michael * Durgnat, Raymond * Caron, Leslie * Pagnol, Marcel * ECRITS, 1926-1971 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - NOVEMBER 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: continued discussions of title, changes to text, translation, illustration, publication, copy of added text on BOUDU, copy of list of illustrations - ECRITS discussions - Continueddiscussions re. publication of CAROLA - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - Re. PETIT THEATRE: continued discussion of subtitling, U.S. distribution Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * CAROLA * Weinberg, Herman * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Andrew, Dudley * ECRITS, 1926-1971 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - DECEMBER 1973
    - Correspondence with Ginette - ECRITS discussions - Re. autobiography: J.R. signs contract with Atheneum, changes, additions to text - brief J.R. discussion with Ginette re. politics Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Truffaut, Francois * Knittel, Robert * Caron, Leslie * Cassan, Marguerite * ECRITS, 1926-1971 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Personal correspondence. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Bogdanovich, Peter * Curtis, Tony (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - JANUARY 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: discussions of photos, corrections, introduction, negotiations with French publishers - Continued discussion re. publication of CAROLA - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - J.R. agrees to be interviewed re. Saint-Exupery Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * CAROLA * FRENCH CANCAN * ORVET * Gallimard, Claude * Saint-Exupery, Antoine de * Braunberger, Pierre (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - FEBRUARY 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Continued efforts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - Re. autobiography: continued discussions of photos, French publication, corrections, introduction - ECRITS discussions - Copy of J.R. letter to the press re. ongoing problems with Paul Renoir - J.R. reaction to scenario of Truffaut's LA NUIT AMERICAINE Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * FRENCH CANCAN * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Renoir, Paul * Truffaut, Francois * Milhaud, Darius * Feinstein, Herbert * Caron, Leslie * ECRITS, 1926-1971 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - MARCH 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. introduction, cover photo, translation - Copy of J.R.'s 1973 financial records - Continued discussion re. publication of CAROLA - Copy of J.R. caption forbook by Mrs. Delmer Daves - Re. PETIT THEATRE: subtitles completed, U.S. premiere scheduled for April Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Bazin, Janine * Avedon, Richard * CAROLA * Flammarion, Henri * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - APRIL 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: continue discussions re. photos, translation, corrections, title, etc. - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - Gallimard declines to publish CAROLA - J.R. comments on French politics - ECRITS published - Editions Balland seeks to publish book on LA GRANDE ILLUSION, J.R. answers questions re. the film - J.R. agrees to rare interview with BBC - PETIT THEATRE premiere in NY Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * CAROLA * Langlois, Henri * ECRITS, 1926-1971 * Simmons, Nina * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * Kael, Pauline * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - MAY 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Re. autobiography: continued discussions re. title, photos, French publication, J.R. corrections to jacket copy, J.R. list of names for publicity quotes - J.R. comment on Giscard d'Estaing - Success of PETIT THEATRE - Discussions re. French broadcast of ORVET Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Truffaut, Francois * ORVET * Garnett, Tay * Millar, Gavin (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - JUNE 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - Search for French theatrical distribution for PETIT THEATRE - Autobiography published in France?, final preparations for English publication - Ginette engaged Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Truffaut, Francois * Gilliatt, Penelope * Bogdanovich, Peter * Simenon, Georges * Milius, John * Cassan, Marguerite (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - JULY 1974
    - Correspondence with Ginette - Project: "Roi d'Yvetot" as stage musical: contract issues - Plan to merge Compagnie Jean Renoir and INTERAMA - Ginette marries, change of name to Anne de Saint Phalle. Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Doynel, Ginette (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - AUGUST 1974
    - Correspondence with Anne (Ginette) - J.R. hospitalized for broken hip - Corrections to Curtiss book on von Stroheim re. Charles Spaak - J.R. interviewed by Jean Marchand - Positif desire to publish J.R * Beylie, Claude * Curtiss, Thomas * Spaak, Charles * Milhaud, Darius * De Saint Phalle, Anne (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - SEPTEMBER 1974
    - Correspondence with Anne de Saint Phalle (maiden name Ginette Doynel) - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - McEldowney plans to exploit THE RIVER in U.S. - Discussion of merging Compagnie Jean Renoir with Truffaut's company - J.R. hospitalized for continued leg problems - Discussions regarding PETIT THEATRE contract - Copy of Gilliatt article on J.R. in NEW YORKER - J.R.'s 80th birthday Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * RIVER, THE * McEldowney, Kenneth * Truffaut, Francois * PETIT THEATRE DE J.R., LE * Sesonske, Alexander * Gilliatt, Penelope * COMPAGNIE DE JEAN RENOIR (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - OCTOBER 1974
    - Correspondence with Anne (Ginette) - LA GRANDE ILLUSION published by Ballard - Continued attempts to obtain copies of old J.R. films - Continued discussions re. THE RIVER contract - Corrections to autobiography - Discussions re. aaptation of LA REGLE DU JEU as stage musical Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * RIVER, THE * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Caron, Leslie * Godden, Rumer * REGLE DU JEU, LA (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - NOVEMBER 1974
    - J.R. thoughts on illness in letter to Truffaut - Continued discussions re. French broadcast of ORVET - MY LIFE AND MY FILMS published, list of photo credits - Sesonske letter: reaction to LA GRANDE ILLUSION publication (errors), discussion of LA BETE HUMAINE Includes correspondence regarding or with: * Truffaut, Francois * ORVET * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Sesonske, Alexander * GRANDE ILLUSION, LA * BETE HUMAINE, LA (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - DECEMBER 1974
    - Correspondence with Anne - 1st royalty statement for MY LIFE AND MY FILMS - Continued discussion of theatrical adaptation of LE REGLE DU JEU - J.R. re-hospitalized - Notes on LA BETE HUMAINE for BBC broadcast - J.R. retrospectivescheduled London February-March Includes correspondence regarding or with: * MY LIFE AND MY FILMS * Saint-Phalle (Ginette Doynel, dite Anne de) * REGLE DU JEU, LA * Truffaut, Francois * Bazin, Janine * Kline, Herbert * Werner, Oskar * BETE HUMAINE, LA (Box 30, Folder 11)